<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Keck</title>
    <description>Software developer with a passion for learning. Posting what inspires me and a few brain dumps.</description>
    <link>http://davidskeck.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://davidskeck.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Annual reading list</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a list of books and articles to read every year. Titles will be switched out as they become stale to me. There will be up to 10 items on this list at a time. Previously listed works are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davidskeck/Annual-Reading-List/blob/master/ARCHIVE.md&quot;&gt;archived&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the latest, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davidskeck/Annual-Reading-List&quot;&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;books&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11878168-anything-you-want&quot;&gt;Anything You Want - Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;articles&quot;&gt;Articles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2014/06/happily-ever-after/372573/&quot;&gt;Masters of love - Emily Esfahani Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/03/jobs/in-defense-of-working-mostly-from-home.html&quot;&gt;Why five days in the office is too many - Prerna Gupta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-27186709&quot;&gt;The slow death of purposeless walking - Finlo Rohrer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/05/26/travel/slow-travel-walking-in-wales.html&quot;&gt;A long, wet walk in Wales - Dominique Browning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/2011/09/15/roger_ebert/&quot;&gt;I do not fear death - Roger Ebert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“As a single footstep will not make a path on the earth, so a single thought will not make a pathway in the mind. To make a deep physical path, we walk again and again. To make a deep mental path, we must think over and over the kind of thoughts we wish to dominate our lives.” - Henry David Thoreau&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like a lot of people read important ideas once and never get the chance to implement them.
The purpose of this list is that ideas that are important to me get the chance to take hold
in my mind. By reading these works annually, I will be introduced to these ideas again
and again until they become habitual to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-me&quot;&gt;Join me!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/calendar/event?action=TEMPLATE&amp;amp;tmeid=XzZ0MTMyZDFwODhvNDZiOWw2Y3MzY2I5azY0cmppYmExNjExM2FiOXA4NG9rNGNpNTg5MWtjaDlpODRfMjAxNTAxMDFUMjAwMDAwWiBkc3RldmVua2Vja0Bt&amp;amp;tmsrc=dstevenkeck%40gmail.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
to add an annual reminder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#100;&amp;#097;&amp;#118;&amp;#105;&amp;#100;&amp;#064;&amp;#107;&amp;#101;&amp;#099;&amp;#107;&amp;#046;&amp;#110;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#063;&amp;#115;&amp;#117;&amp;#098;&amp;#106;&amp;#101;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#061;&amp;#065;&amp;#110;&amp;#110;&amp;#117;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#032;&amp;#082;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#100;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#032;&amp;#076;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&quot;&gt;Email me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 05:40:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidskeck.github.io/blog/2014/07/15/readinglist/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidskeck.github.io/blog/2014/07/15/readinglist/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>There are no rules</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, and, likely because I just graduated, I’ve been hearing dubious
business advice like crazy. Stuff like “Don’t show your weaknesses”, and
“Pretend to know everything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure it’s all well meaning, but, to me, it’s all garbage. It might be
fine if you want to get a job under false pretenses or plan on getting a position
that isn’t right for you or your employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I don’t know a certain technology and I get asked about it in an interview, I always
say directly that I don’t know anything about that, but I would be willing to
learn. And, that’s only if I’m actually interested in learning it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to expose my ignorance. Then I get to learn. If I come into a job
acting like I know all about everything, I don’t get that chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking, this guy has no idea about the “real-world” job market.
And, you would be right! I think my naiveté and optimism will to serve me well.
I don’t have to lie or feel pressured to perform in something I’ve never even
given myself a chance to learn. I’m not disenchanted, and I can bring passion
along with programming skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, you know, I might not get the job that I thought I wanted. But that’s fine
too. I have the luxury right now of being able to say no and accepting when
companies do the same. I don’t have a family to support or any expenses
that a minimum wage job couldn’t float for at least a few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just know I would be much happier working at a Starbucks than under the
thumb of some corporation that strangles my spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to protect your spark of optimism and hope with everything you have. Too
many people give up too soon or think that these are just the rules of the business world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no rules. Do what makes sense to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:david@keck.net?subject=There are no rules&quot;&gt;Email me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 07:49:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidskeck.github.io/blog/2014/07/13/norules/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidskeck.github.io/blog/2014/07/13/norules/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;Anything You Want&quot; - Book review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11878168-anything-you-want&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://davidskeck.github.io/assets/DerekSivers-AnythingYouWant-300x378.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Anything You Want Cover&quot; title=&quot;Anything You Want - Derek Sivers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the chance to read this book about a week ago. I expected to just
read the first few pages before heading into work, but I found it so enthralling that
I read the whole thing that morning. It only took about an hour, just like
Derek said it would in the first chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can tell, this book is pretty short. The content feels almost obsessively
pared down to the most relevant message possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this book is because its voice is so lucid. Everything was so clear and
easy to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chapters of the book are just dripping with understanding. Each scenario
offers a chance to see a new perspective and step back from what might be
considered “common sense” to illuminate an important insight that was made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the book, Sivers invites anyone who has “made it this far” to email him
with any comments or questions. I took advantage of this offer and I received an email
back the very next day. It is obvious he cares about his readers, and it was
nice to know that Sivers embodies the qualities he discusses in this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I learned a lot, and I definitely laughed a lot, but the most
important thing I experienced from reading this book was an overwhelming
sense of optimism and empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rating-1010&quot;&gt;Rating: 10/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:david@keck.net?subject=Anything You Want - Book review&quot;&gt;Email me.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 11:10:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidskeck.github.io/blog/bookreview/2014/07/07/anything/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidskeck.github.io/blog/bookreview/2014/07/07/anything/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
