<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Keck</title>
    <description>Software developer with a passion for learning. Posting what inspires me and a few brain dumps.</description>
    <link>http://davidskeck.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://davidskeck.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;Anything You Want&quot; - Book review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://davidskeck.github.io/assets/DerekSivers-AnythingYouWant-300x378.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Anything You Want Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11878168-anything-you-want&quot;&gt;Anything You Want - Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the chance to read this book about a week ago. I expected to just
read the first few pages before heading into work, but I found it so enthralling that
I read the whole thing that morning. It only took about an hour, just like
Derek said it would in the first chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can tell, this book is pretty short. The content feels almost obsessively
pared down to the most relevant message possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this book is because its voice is so lucid.
Such clarity is something I admire and want to learn myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the book, Sivers invites anyone who has “made it this far” to email him
with any comments or questions. I took advantage of this offer and I received an email
back the very next day. It is obvious he cares about his readers. It was great to see
that Sivers embodies the qualities he discusses in this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section&quot;&gt;10/10&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 11:10:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidskeck.github.io/blog/bookreview/2014/07/07/anything/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidskeck.github.io/blog/bookreview/2014/07/07/anything/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello.</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-am-i&quot;&gt;Who am I?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m David Keck. I just graduated this May with a Bachelor of Computer Science. I love computers, and I started programming when I was about twelve or thirteen in BASIC. Currently, I’m working at NASA as an intern, making flight software for an in-development satellite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-this-site&quot;&gt;What is this site?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my personal website where I’ll be posting information about my projects, thoughts, and ideas. I’ll also be linking to anything I find interesting with “Link Love” posts every now and then. (Thanks for the idea, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marksdailyapple.com&quot;&gt;Mark Sisson&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-can-i-contact-you&quot;&gt;How can I contact you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have noticed, this website is lacking a comment section. This was partially intentional, and also partially because I am just learning the art of web design. If you have any comments or questions about anything you see on this website, feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#100;&amp;#097;&amp;#118;&amp;#105;&amp;#100;&amp;#064;&amp;#107;&amp;#101;&amp;#099;&amp;#107;&amp;#046;&amp;#110;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;.  Use the title of the post as the email 
subject so I can better respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-your-favorite-color&quot;&gt;What’s your favorite color?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Single favorite? Dark blue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Favorite combination? Dark green and dark grey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 07:40:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidskeck.github.io/blog/2014/07/03/hello/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidskeck.github.io/blog/2014/07/03/hello/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
