<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Keck</title>
    <description>Software developer with a passion for learning. Periodic updates on current projects, thoughts, problems, solutions, and ideas.</description>
    <link>http://www.davidskeck.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.davidskeck.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Show, don&#39;t tell.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’m in the middle of an internship at Marshall Space Flight Center
in Huntsville, AL. It has been great so far. The people I’m working with are
very intelligent. They are also easy to learn from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s part of how I know they’re intelligent. They can explain
complex concepts because of how they use analogies, metaphors, and demonstrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s an interesting lesson to be learned here, apart from all the great
software development knowledge that they are imparting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you want to explain a difficult concept: show, don’t tell. I don’t mean
you have to have props or a whiteboard. If none of those are sensible, try
to think of a great metaphor or another easy to imagine scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this helps a lot. I also have noticed that it keeps the audience
much more engaged. For example, I recently attended a tour of an electric
propulsion laboratory. I know nothing about electric propulsion, but thanks to
the skilled presentation of the concepts I left feeling like I at
least understood the very basic function of an extremely complex subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the speaker was describing the forces at play, he held his hand out as far
as he could and blew onto it as strongly as he could. He encouraged others to do
the same (which definitely increased audience engagement). He said this was near
the level of force produced from one of the ion propulsion thrusters. It was
fascinating to realize that such a small force could be used to propel small
satellites in space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without his demonstration, such a real understanding of the forces at play
would have been lost on the audience. Like, if he had just said X millinewtons,
I would have had no idea what that felt like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to impart knowledge is an important skill, even if you never
give another presentation again. If you can clearly explain your problems, proposed
solutions, or ideas, you’re much more likely to get the response you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could probably fill a book with all the things I am learning from this
opportunity. I hope to have a few more posts about my experience this summer.
Thank you for following along.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 14:49:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.davidskeck.com/blog/nasa/internship/presentation/2014/06/28/show-dont-tell/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.davidskeck.com/blog/nasa/internship/presentation/2014/06/28/show-dont-tell/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
